## Gabriel B. Casella

CONTACT INFORMATION http://gbc921.github.io

e-mail: qabrielbcasella@gmail.com

SKILLS **BACKGROUND** 

Linux user since 2007 and Arch Linux user since 3 years ago, is really interested in system and network administration. Knows about ns-3 (wireless), iptables, NAT, OpenFlow, OpenWrt, Apache web server and wired/wireless protocols in general.

Instructor of Linux survival guide for freshmen as part of the UTFPR open-source group.

**EDUCATION** 

Bachelor of Science

Expected graduation: 2014

Federal Technological University of Paraná

Ponta Grossa, PR, Brazil

Major: Computer Science

CAPES-CsF exchange student program:

Bachelor of Science January 2012 – December 2012

**Western Michigan University** 

Kalamazoo, MI

Major: Computer Science

COMPUTER SKILLS

Shell Script, LaT<sub>E</sub>X 2<sub>€</sub>, C++, C#, Java, Python 2, SQL, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, Office and LibreOffice, Virtualbox, DHCP, IEEE 802.11, CSMA/CA.

EXPERIENCE

PROFESSIONAL UTFPR - Federal Technological University of Paraná, Ponta Grossa, Paraná, Brazil *Undergraduate Research* March 2011 - December 2011

- Worked with a desktop grid distributed system, written in Java focused on the balance of price integration among the cooperatives, the client and the server;
- Designed a simple Wordpress theme;
- Integrated PHP on Apache Tomcat.

EPROM, Bauru, São Paulo, Brazil

Computer Tech

**January 2010 – March 2010** 

- Configured Windows systems to work properly, installing drivers, cleaning or reinstalling the system;
- Introduced anti-virus scanning/backup with a Linux Live CD instead of removing and inserting the hard drive from/to the computer's client. This made possible to do multiple scans/backup at the same time.